



# **Hilalnur Beral**

Date of birth: 28 Nov 1998 | Nationality: Turkish | Gender: Female |

Phone number: (+90) 5313669104 (Mobile) | Email address:

beralhilal@gmail.com | LinkedIn:

https://tr.linkedin.com/in/hilalnur-beral-istqb®-768b21184

Whatsapp Messenger: +905313669104

Address: Çankaya/Ankara, 06000, Ankara, Türkiye (Work)

#### **ABOUT ME**

In 2021, I graduated from the Computer Engineering Department at TED University with a GPA of 3.56. I also completed a minor program in World Citizenship at the Faculty of Economics and Administrative Sciences. I participated in a research project on Augmented Reality and Virtual Reality under the leadership of Assoc. Prof. Dr. Can Baran Aktaş from TED University's Department of Civil Engineering. Our article titled 'Augmented Reality and Virtual Reality Integration into the Construction Industry' covers the applications of AR and VR technologies in different fields, including the software programs used.

#### EDUCATION AND TRAINING

15 SEP 2016 - 11 JUN 2021 ANKARA, Türkiye

# **COMPUTER ENGINEER** TED University

In 2021, I graduated from the Computer Engineering Department at TED University with a GPA of 3.56. I also completed a minor program in World Citizenship at the Faculty of Economics and Administrative Sciences. I participated in a research project on Augmented Reality and Virtual Reality under the leadership of Assoc. Prof. Dr. Can Baran Aktaş from TED University's Department of Civil Engineering. Our article titled 'Augmented Reality and Virtual Reality Integration into the Construction Industry' covers the applications of AR and VR technologies in different fields, including the software programs used. From February 8, 2021, to October 21, 2022, I worked as an avionics software test engineer at BİTES Defense and Aerospace Industry Company. Since October 24, 2022, I have been working as a test engineer at HAVELSAN company."

**Website** https://aday.tedu.edu.tr/? gclid=Cj0KCQjwib2mBhDWARIsAPZUn\_ntJvmS87x3zjbs8rbr2JNb8LhtosVTzfCZbx2HRPVYfaeMW-f3Z9oaAonQEALw\_wcB

Field of study Engineering and engineering trades not elsewhere classified Final grade 3,56

### WORK EXPERIENCE

2 SEP 2021 - 21 OCT 2022 ANKARA, Türkiye

# AVIONICS SOFTWARE TEST ENGINEER BİTES DEFENSE AND AEROSPACE INDUSTRY COMPANY

In this position, I was involved in defense industry projects. I worked as an avionics software test engineer for the Sikorsky general-purpose helicopter.

# I was responsible for:

- -Analyzing software requirement
- -Designing and prioritizing test cases.
- -Executing test cases
- -Reporting bugs to software developer
- -Managing software problem change request process with software developer.
- -Retest resolved bugs , regression test when needed



24 OCT 2022 - CURRENT ANKARA. Türkive

# SOFTWARE AND SYSTEM TEST ENGINEER HAVELSAN DEFENSE COMPANY

As part of this position, I am working on a domestic and national radar project. I am responsible for both software and system testing. My primary responsibilities include preparing test procedures, executing them, and reporting the results. To conduct system tests, I am physically present at the sites where the radars are installed. Jira and Confluence are actively used in our projects. Using these tools can significantly improve team collaboration, project management, and overall productivity.

AUG 2019 - SEP 2019 ANKARA, Türkiye

#### **INTERN** KAREL ELECTRONICS

Performing project testing and implementing the desired changes in the test environment on Oracle APEX. Utilizing HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, and SQL.

JUN 2020 - AUG 2020 ANKARA, Türkiye

**INTERN** ASELSAN DEFENSE COMPANY

Due to confidentiality reasons related to the defense industry project, project details cannot be disclosed. During the internship period, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python Flask Framework, PostgreSQL, and pgAdmin were used.

#### LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): TURKISH

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
ENGLISH	C1	C1	C1	C1	C1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

#### DIGITAL SKILLS

MS Office | Java | Python | Confluence | Jira | Linux

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

## **DRIVING LICENCE**

**Driving Licence:** B

## **HOBBIES AND INTERESTS**

**Swimming** 

**Pilates** 

Reading

### **CONFERENCES AND SEMINARS**

7 MAY 2021 - 9 MAY 2021 - Online

**International Congress of Engineering and Natural Sciences Studies** Virtual Reality (VR) and Augmented Reality (AR) technologies are considered to be one of the most influential technologies anticipated soon to transform the architecture, engineering, and construction (AEC) industry through benefits in scheduling and project progress tracking, quality and defect management, time and cost management, employee and safety training. The goal of the study was to assess both technologies in terms of their reported advantages and shortcomings and identify and map hardware and software needs to aid institutions



planning to implement such technology by providing a practical framework from which to initiate.

The certificate will be shared with you upon request

Link https://www.voutube.com/watch?v=vWbwRFpfCHY

20 MAY 2021 - 21 MAY 2021 - Online

International Conference of Contemporary Affairs in Architecture and Urbanism VirtualReality (VR)and AugmentedReality (AR)technologies are regarded as one of the most prominent technologies that are expected to change the architecture, engineering, and construction (AEC) industryin the near future. The goal of the study was to assess both technologies in terms of their reported advantages and shortcomings as well as discuss challenges for their widespread implementation, identify and map hardware/software needs to aid institutions planning to implement such technology by providing a practical framework from which to initiate.

## **PUBLICATIONS**

### **Detecting Fake News on Big Data** - 2021

In this study, we developed a new framework for detecting fake news, which has recently become a significant problem in social media. We compared the performances of different machine learning approaches. It becomes a challenging problem to detect fake news effectively. Apache Spark's machine learning environment, where many processors can work simultaneously, offers a very suitable environment for dealing with big data classification problems. After experiments using Naïve Bayes, Neural Network, Logistic regression, and Support Vector Machine on large datasets we obtained on Kaggle showed that our software can report up to 99% accuracy rates.

**Link** https://dergipark.org.tr/en/pub/researcher/issue/68089/984460